16 Wintersweet Way, Irvine, CA 92612 — rvijax@gmail.com — (949) 394-0397

## Personal Profile

I am an engineer at Bimaple Technology Inc, an early stage startup by UC Irvine Computer Science Professor Chen Li. Previously, I worked under Prof. Chen as a graduate student in the Information Systems Group. I worked on Interactive Query Suggestion and Auto-Completion on large scale systems. My interests are in information retrieval and databases. I have hands-on experience with engineering challenges in building fast search engines.

#### Education

## University of California -Irvine

MS in Computer Science

Thesis: Interactive Query Suggestion.

Adviser: Prof. Chen Li

# SSN College of Engineering, Anna University-India

May 2004 - July 2008

Sep 2008 - May 2010

GPA: 3.69/4.0

Bachelor of Engineering (*Honors*) in Computer Science and Engineering 69% (no GPA system) Senior Project: Parallel Biological Neuronal Network simulations using petrinets.

Advisor: Prof. N. Venkateswaran. Work published in Neuroinformatics'08.

## Experience

#### Bimaple Technology Inc.

Irvine, CA

Software Engineer

Jun 2010 - Present

Designed and implemented the first vertical-search product of Bimaple. The live demo of the product is at (http://bimaple.com/demos).

## iPubmed - Information Systems Group, UCI

Graduate Student

Advisor: Prof.Chen Li, UCI

Jul 2009 - May 2010

Designed and implemented Interactive Query Suggestion in iPubmed (http://ipubmed.ics.uci.edu) as part of my MS thesis. Highlights are novel In-Memory, Trie based index structure in C++ with application residing on Apache-FastCgi server, talking AJAX/JSON through Python scripts.

## Waran Research Foundation

Student Programmer, Part-Time

Chennai, India, http://warftindia.org

Sep 2006 - July 2008

Experience in Parallel Programming and Linux Cluster Administration. I implemented middleware to map scientific models to compute clusters using C++, Boost MPI. I wrote Python scripts to automate build testing and collecting performance stats for this middleware.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: C, C++ (STL,Boost), Python, Java, Javascript

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, DB2

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Application Server: Apache HTTP, TOMCAT

Tools and IDE: gmake, gdb, FastCGI, LingPipe, Eclipse, Matlab

# Research/ Projects

#### Improving PubMed search using Topic Models

Python

I implemented the following search engine components in Python: Tokeniser, Stemmer, Topic based indexing and browsing system of medical publications in PubMed.

## Virtual World in HTML5

Javascript, AJAX

I designed and implemented a game-like tool to define real world building maps. Rendering the given map in 3D for navigation and leaving post-it like tags using only HTML5 over http.

#### Blind Man's Eve

C++ - Microsoft Imagine Cup

Undergrad Team of 3 project to build a text recognition system using camera on mobile devices, to help the blind people. I implemented the image processing components using C++ and openCV. Project was selected as one of *Top 12 projects from India in Microsoft Imagine Cup*'2006.

# Relevant Courses

Database Management, Information Retrieval, Analysis of Algorithms, Machine Learning, Image Understanding, Multimedia Systems Design, Scientific Computing, Probablistic Learning.